KELEBET ENGIDA

Seattle, WA 98107 | Phone: 206-307-7869 | Email: kelebetaengida@gmail.com LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kelebet-engida-5825a8160 GitHub:https://qithub.com/kelebetengida | Portfolio: https://kelebetportfolio.herokuapp.com

SUMMARY

Dedicated and efficient Full-stack Agile Developer with an Environmental Science degree (focusing on remote sensing data analytical skills) from the University of Washington. Have intermediate experience in Python (panda library). Well-rounded professional with communication and organizational skills. I really enjoy using my skill sets to support the entrepreneurial culture of startups and big companies.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML-Proficient, CSS- Intermediate, JQuery, Bootstrap- Intermediate, React.js **Applications:** Local Storage, Session Storage-Basic, Handlebars, DataBase (MySQL, SQL, MongoDB) -Basic, Python-Basic, API, JSON, AJAX, Node.js, Express, User Authentication, JavaScript- Intermediate

EDUCATION

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development: University of Washington, Seattle, WA 2021 A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Full-stack (front-end & back-end) web development.

Bachelor's Science degree: University of Washington, Seattle, WA 2021 B.S Oceanography, College of Environment

PROJECTS

Family Knowledge Exchange |github.com/ManuhuiaBarcham/family-knowledge-exchange.git |fierce-island-14478.herokuapp.com/

- An application that links together different individuals and stakeholder groups interested in supporting families, allowing them to connect and share knowledge in their respective fields.
- Full-Stack Developer, Project manager, built front-end components and connecting to back-end as well as building the schema
- Express.js, React.js, Node.js, MongoDB, GraphQL, Apollo-Server-Express, Styled-Component, Bootstrap, Heroku

Life Happens | github.com/ywkuo227/life-happens.gitb | ywkuo227.github.io/life-happens/

- The application allows users to have a quick glance at their day with an interface displaying the weather of the day, an interactive to-do list, stock market performance data, and local news.
- News API fetching and CSS design of the page.
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Jquery, CSS Bulma, CSS Font Awesome, API

Facility Management System | github.com/DN-Vanguard/Facility_Management.git | dn-fac-mgmt.herokuapp.com/login

- Built for facility management and company logistics teams to view their employees in different departments, floors, and office spaces.
- Handlebar views, Api routes, and building the models
- Handlebars, JavaScript, NodeJs, Express.is, MySql, Insomnia Core, Heroku, Bootstrap, Sequelize, moment, Handlebars-date format (3rd Party Library)

EXPERIENCE

Airbnb Host Photographer Freelance

2020 - Present Seattle, WA

• Hosted photography events to the greater Seattle area to customers which creates unique and memorable photos.

2019 Intern

Atom- Leap

Berlin, Germany

- Supported teams meeting project deadlines by collecting and refining data using python
- Wrote environmental articles for the company's blog website often under the pressure of a timeline to create awareness in sustainable business practices for startups.
- https://hightechseedlab.com/2019/02/15/the-dilemma-of-environmental-startups-today/
- https://hightechseedlab.com/2019/03/29/how-to-make-vour-business-a-little-greener/

Research Assistant **Seattle Children's Research Institute**

2018 - 2019

Seattle, WA

- Maintained lab databases for up-to-date data support research teams.
- Troubleshooting difficulties with assays and protocols prevented problems of low or no signal in samples.
- Processed and organized specimens leading to organized workflow in lab space.

Interpretive Science Educator

2015 - 2019

Pacific Science Center

Seattle, WA

- Performed in-depth science content presentations to museum quests producing a scientific dialog.
- Taught science topics to the younger audience in low-income communities inspiring scientific curiosity and filling the summer learning gap.
- Collaborated with local scientists to design interactive activities and presentations for all age groups where guests had a maximum content engagement.